<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>#semanticClimate</title>
	<subtitle>Liberating knowledge from climate-related reports</subtitle>
	
	<link href="/p/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href=""/>
	<updated>2022-10-22T09:25:23Z</updated>
	<id>https://semanticclimate.netlify.app/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Semantic Climate</name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title></title>
		<link href="/p/en/posts/oaweek_intro/"/>
		<updated>2022-10-22T09:25:01Z</updated>
		<id>/p/en/posts/oaweek_intro/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;OA Week 2022: Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really excited to offer #semanticClimate for OA week. It&#39;s a relatively new way of communicating complex topics and
it&#39;s best understood by actually &amp;quot;learning by doing&amp;quot;. Don&#39;t be frightened by &amp;quot;semantic&amp;quot;; it means using machines to help
with the bits machines are good at ([https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web]), freeing human brains to do what they are best at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;climate&amp;quot; is complex! No human understands everything, so it&#39;s critical to link different resources: data, text, simulations, etc. &amp;quot;semantic&amp;quot; means they can all talk to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: &amp;quot;what does &#39;GHG&#39; mean and why does it matter?&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Just a post</title>
		<link href="/p/en/posts/thishastostayhere/"/>
		<updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>/p/en/posts/thishastostayhere/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Headline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In duis sit enim eu incididunt consequat qui culpa amet qui officia veniam voluptate consectetur. Magna velit ex do duis ut aute. Dolor qui labore Lorem ullamco voluptate eiusmod voluptate pariatur occaecat velit sunt id consequat duis. Irure minim quis irure dolor mollit nulla deserunt nisi sunt aute tempor occaecat. Non incididunt sit officia dolor nulla nulla laborum deserunt dolore sint voluptate elit esse quis. Dolore proident cillum nostrud magna duis in mollit ad labore incididunt enim aute tempor. Cillum consectetur esse esse duis labore consequat aliquip enim ea pariatur veniam occaecat sunt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>